Guide to the Daniel Bell Research Files on U.S. Communism, Socialism, and the Labor Movement TAM.080
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: The American Socialist Party
  - Subseries IV:I: The Socialist Party and the United Auto Workers, 1937-1941
    The Socialist Party actively participated in the formation and the early struggles of the UAW Some appreciation of this activity can be gained from the Socialist Auto League materials in this section: bulletins and reports for 1938 and 1939, minutes of the National Steering Committee, 1938, and reports of the National Action Committee, 1938. These are supplemented by the correspondence of Arthur McDowell, Ben Fisher, Gerry Allard, Roy Burt, and Norman Thomas concerning the UAW, 1937-1939, and SP policy statements, reports and miscellaneous bulletins on the situation, 1937-1941.
    - Socialist Party and the United Automobile Workers Union. Contents: Letters and memos on S.P. activities and policies in auto; Gerry Allard, editor of The Socialist Call, correspondence on the situation in auto, 1937 1938; Roy Burt, Executive Secretary, correspondence on auto, 1937 1939; Norman Thomas, correspondence on auto, 1938 1939; Socialist Auto League Reports, 1938 1939; Contents: Socialist Auto League Bulletins, 1938; Minutes of the National Steering Committee, Socialist Auto League, 1938; Reports of the National Action Committee, Socialist Auto League, 1938; Policy statements, reports, pamphlets and miscellaneous bulletins concerning the auto situation, 1937 1941; Report issued by Homer Martin concerning a Communist Party meeting with auto leaders. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Subseries IV:J: The Socialist Party: 1940-1941
    The SP's militant antiwar position proved intolerable, not only to much of the Party's rank and file, but also to such leading socialists as Alfred Baker Lewis, Paul Porter, Arthur McDowell, and Jack Altman. Party statements, miscellaneous minutes of the National Executive Committee and the National Action Committee, and antiwar propaganda, including the text of Norman Thomas's speech at Madison Square Garden (May 24, 1941), explaining the official position. The opposition is represented by statements, resignations, and correspondence, particularly the correspondence of Arthur McDowell, who fought unsuccessfully to change the Party's position.
    - McDowell, Arthur: Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Minutes: National Action Committee, National Executive Committee; Miscellaneous Papers and Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - National Convention Records (folder 1), 1940 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - National Convention Records (folder 2), 1940 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - News clippings: Newsclippings and newspapers concerning the Socialists and the war from The Socialist Call 1941, The Tribune(England) 1940, The New Leader 1941., 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Positions (pro, anti) on World War II; SP, including the text of Norman Thomas' speech at Madison Square Garden, May 24, 1941; Letters and statements of prominent socialists against the SP's anti war position, particularly Alfred Baker Lewis, Paul Porter, Arthur McDowell, Jack Altman., 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Subseries IV:K: The Socialist Party: 1942 present
    This section includes a variety of materials: National Convention Papers and election propaganda from the 1940's; bulletins issued by "left wing" tendencies within the party; Hammer and Tongs, 1940-1946 (incomplete); literature of the Conference of American Progressives, 1946, the National Educational Committee for a New Party, 1946-1947, and the North Dakota Non Partisan League; minutes of the National Executive Committee, 1943-1945, and of the National Action Committee, 1943-1946; and SP statements on the war and the Marshall Plan. A few files are devoted to articles and notes on Norman Thomas.
    - North Dakota Non-Partisan League, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Socialist Party Papers Contents include: Appeal to the President of Mexico on behalf of left wing refugees, 1942; Statements of the "Committee on Socialist Perspectives", 1943, together with Perspectives, bulletin of the "Committee on Socialist Perspectives", 1943; Miscellaneous National Convention Papers, 1942; Report of the New York State S.P. Convention, June, 1942; Newark, New Jersey, S.P. branch statement on the war, 1942; Miscellaneous National Convention Papers, 1944; Election material, 1944; Miscellaneous National Convention Papers, 1946; Report of Norman Thomas' statement on war, 1945; S.P. statement on the San Francisco conference and on the Marshall Plan; "Toward a Revolutionary Organization" by Jim Dinsmoor, 1945 ?; "To the Left" by Harry Kantor, a discussion of intra party politics; Letters and statements concerning third party efforts 1944 1947, particularly the Conference of American Progressives, April 1946, and National Education Committee for a New Party, 1946 1947, 1942-1947 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Minutes: National Action Committee, 1943-1946 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Minutes: National Executive Committee, 1943-1945 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Socialist Party Papers & Clippings, 1940s-1950s (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Thomas, Norman: Articles and Notes, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Subseries IV:L: International Socialism
    Scope and Contents note
    Articles, clippings and publications concerning Social Democratic Parties and Social Democratic influence in the labor movement since World War II. Some background information on the first and second Internationals, and the roots of socialism in England and France. The emphasis is on Europe, particularly England, France, Germany and Austria, but there is also information on Asia, Africa and the Middle East.
    - Bandung: Nationalities, Nationalism, 1956-1957 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - British Labor: World War II, Ideology, 1941-1943 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - CIO: Formal Ideology, 1956-1957 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - European Socialism: Socialist International, post-WWII, 1953-1956 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Labor, 1935, 1952-1956 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Nasser: Suez Adventure / Middle East, 1956 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - New Zealand Labour Party, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Political Socialism / Radicalism - French Socialist Party, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Politics, Europe - Italian Socialism, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Radicalism, Socialist Parties, Socialist International Revival, post-WWII, 1951-1954 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Radicalism/Social Movements: The First International; History of the Internationals, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Social Movements. Post-War: Austrian SP - Changes in Party Structure, 1954 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Social Movements. Post-War: German SP - Changing Ideology, undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Socialism, Europe: French Socialist Party, Pre WWI, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Socialism, Europe: New Roads (Documents), 1952 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Socialist International, Third Congress: Asia, Colonialism, etc., 1953 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Social Movements - Ideology - Asia and the West, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Socialist Parties, Asia, 1954 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Socialist Party, Austria - Civil War, 1934 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Socialist Parties, France, 1955-1958 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Socialist Parties, Great Britain, 1954 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Socialist Parties, Great Britain: Fabianism, Dilemmas of Power, 1949-1955 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Socialist Parties, India - Factionalism, 1916, 1954-1958 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Socialist Theory, Revisions: Fabianism (Great Britain), 1952 (Box 31, Folder 13)
- Series V: Princeton Conference on Socialism and American Life
  Daniel Bell was one of the participants in the Conference on Socialism and American Life held at Princeton University, 1946-1947. His contribution to the Conference, "The Background and Development of Marxian Socialism in the United States," was published in Socialism and American Life edited by Donald D. Egbert and Stow Persons (Princeton University Press, 1952). This section of the collection contains the conference guide and the manuscript of Marxian Socialism..." along with relevant notes and articles.
  - Conference guide for the Conference on Socialism and American Life held at Princeton University, 1946 1947 (Includes typescripts of papers delivered), undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Daniel Bell: "The Background and Development of Marxian Socialism in the United States." MS, later published in Donald D. Egbert and Stow Persons (eds.) Socialism and American Life, Princeton University Press, 1952., undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Marxian Socialism: Correspondence and Clippings, undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Marxian Socialism: Chapter III, undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Marxian Socialism: Chapter IV, undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Marxian Socialism: Chapter VIII, undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Marxian Socialism: Chapter VI, undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Marxian Socialism: Chapter VI: Research materials, undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
- Series VI: Communist Party and its Relations with the American Labor Movement
  The material in this part of the collection is primarily concerned with Communist Party activity in the labor movement during the 1920s and 1930s. There are several historical essays on CP development; a short study of the left wing in American trade unions, 1921-1925; and a history of the Party in the Food Workers Industrial Union. These studies in manuscript are supplemented by articles from communist and labor journals concerning CP labor policies and factional disputes and, in some cases, lengthy interviews with leading figures. Extensive reading notes on the political left and on communist influence in labor, particularly in the needle trades and in coal, and notes on CP minutes complete the section. The minutes are from the Political Committee, 1925-1928; the Trade Union Educational League and the Trade Union Unity League; the Trade Union Committee of the Central Executive Committee, 1923-1927; and a Party Conference, 1930.
  - Volume I, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Volume II, undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Volume III, undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Volume IV, undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Volume V, undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Volume VI, undated (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Volume VII, undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Volume VIII, undated (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Carpenters Union, undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Chicago, Role of as Radical Center, undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Coal Mining Industry: Trade Union Committee of TUC (includes Foster reports), 1927 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Communist International. 2nd Congress: Syndicalist Issue, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Communist International. 3rd Congress: Discussion of Union Question (in German), 1921 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - CPUSA Agitprop Dept. Instructions [from Browder file], 1929 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - CPUSA 8th Convention. Documents and Correspondence, 1934 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Draft of Economic Article/Attack on Lovestone [from Browder file], 1929 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - IWW Role within/Communications with PROFINTERN [from Browder file], 1922-1923 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - National Training School. Jan-Mar 1934, Report on (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Needle Trader[from Browder file], 1929 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Political Committee Secretariat Minutes (source: Gitlow copies). Includes Letters to/from Communist International on organization, 1925-1928 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Red Aid, Other CP/CI Material; "Rationalisation in the U.S.", 1930 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - TUEL/TUUL Minutes, Reports, etc., 1924-1927 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Steel/Packinghouse Campaign of 1919 (ts.), undated (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Youth Work, Emphasis on [Draft Thesis for the NEC Plenum], 1930 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - American Labor Party; Brookwood Labor College; Conference for Progressive Labor Action - articles on, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Brookwood Labor College: Conflict at, 1933 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Comintern History [published articles], undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Needle Trades, 1920s: notes on, undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Open Letter, 1933 - Transformation of CP (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Radicalism and Musteites; Founding of AWP [clippings], 1930s (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - A Short History of the CPUSA [ts, 66 pp], undated (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - TUEL Central Executive Committee - notes on, undated (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - TUEL Minutes, 1923-27 - notes on, undated (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - TUEL National Committee, 1923-24 - notes on, undated (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - TUEL - Programs, Reports, etc., undated, 1927 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - TUEL - "Resolution on the Broadening of…", undated (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Browder, Earl: Autobiography [notes on], undated (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Browder, Earl: "The Left-Wing in the American Trade Unions, 1921-1925" [ts, 16 pp], undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Browder, Earl: "Strategy and Tactics of World Communism." [U.S. Senate Internal Security Act testimony], Oct 6, 1955 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - CP Attitude toward Labor, 1919-21 [notes on], undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - CP Organizational Conference of 1930 [notes on], undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - CP Political Committee Minutes, 1926-27 [notes on, undated (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Foster, William Z. "From Bryan to Stalin." [notes on], undated (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Amalgamated Metal Workers, undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - American Negro Labor Congress, undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Bittelman, Alex, undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Changing Character of Labor Leadership, undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Communist Party of America, undated (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Communist Labor Party, undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Communist International, undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Communist Control of Labor Unions (Theory), undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - The Communist: List of articles on Negroes & Trade Unions, undated (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - The Coal Digger, Oct 1928 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Dubinsky, David - Clippings, undated (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Empire in Wood: A History of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters [PhD abstract], May 1905 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Farmer Labor Party (Chicago, General), undated (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Farmer Labor Communist Party ( New Republic article), Jul 1924 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Foster, William Z. The Great Steel Strike and its Lessons[excerpts], undated (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Foster, William Z. Leaves from a Workers Life, undated (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Frey, John - Interviews by William Goldsmith (ts, 63 pp), Nov 10, 1955 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - International Fur & Leather Workers Union, undated (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Labor Age(Brophy), Nov 1922 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Labor Herald (re Coal), Dec 1922 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Labor in Politics (MA thesis abstract), 1949 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Labor Unity; Labor Unity (topic), 1926-1927 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Left Wing Unions, undated (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Lusk Committee Reports, 1920 (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Manley, Joseph, undated (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Men and Coal(Coleman) excerpts, undated (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - National Miners Union, undated (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - National Save the Miners Union Committee, undated (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Quill, Michael, undated (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Red International of Labor Unions, undated (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Rochester, Anna: Labor and Coal, 1931 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Ruthenberg, C.E., Oct 1925 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - San Francisco General Strike, undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Saposs, David: Readings in Trade Unionism, undated (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Socialist Party - Left Wing of, undated (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Transport Workers Union of America, undated (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - TUEL (Practice), undated (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - United Mine Workers Journal, Sep 1928 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - United Rubber Workers of America, undated (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Workers (Communist) Party, undated (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Zimmerman, Sascha, undated (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Bill Haywood's Book- Notes, undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Brophy, John - Interview Notes, undated (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Browder, Earl - Correspondence re Interview, 1955 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Browder, Earl - What the Left Wing Has Accomplished, undated (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Browder, Earl - Interview Notes, undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Cannon, James P., undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Communism and U.S. Social Structure: Differentiated Vulnerability, undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Corker, Charles E.: Some Observations on Study of the Communist Problem (ts., 39 pp), 1954 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - CPUSA: Early Years, Views of J.P. Cannon, undated (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Fund for the Republic Project: Karsh, Garman tss, undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Fund for the Republic Project: Political Economy, TUEL, undated (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Fund for the Republic Project: Replies to Outlines, 1955 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Gitlow, Ben, undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Hapgood, Powers, undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Howat, Alexander, undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations Hearings (1952): Baldwin Letter to William Z. Foster, 1922 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Labor Herald, undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Lewis, John L., undated (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Ralph Chaplin, Wobbly: The Rough and Tumble Story of an American Radical, 1948 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Rosenbaum, Arthur (Barbers & Beauty Culturists of America): Interview re NYC CIO Council, undated (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Widick, B.J.: Memo to DB re CP in the Automobile Industry, 1956 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Bell, Daniel: Correspondence, Fund for the Republic Project, 1956-1957 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Bell, Daniel: Labor Outline, Bibliography, Correspondence (FFR), 1955 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Browder, Earl: American Communist Parties Under Attack, undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Browder, Earl: Interviews with Dan Bell and Bill Goldsmith - Notes and Excerpts [thick file], 1955-1956 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Browder, Earl: Relations between the Communist Party and the Communist International(ts, 40 pp - memo for Theodore Draper), Nov 11, 1955 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - The Caligari World of Underground Communism, undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Communism and Government (ts.), undated (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Communist Party, 1919-1924, undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Donnelly, Ignatius, undated (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Fund for the Republic Bibliography(work plan, memos, etc.), 1956 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Intelligentsia and Communism; Review of Whitaker Chambers' Witness, undated (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - IWW [thick file], undated (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Labor Movement, US - History, Theory, Jewish Labor, undated (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Melancholy Intermezzo (re 1919), undated (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Needle Trades Bibliography, undated (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Pullman Strike, Eugene Debs, undated (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Radical Mentality - Jack London's The Iron Heel, undated (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - The Schooling of Abraham Cahan, 1954 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Sinclair, Upton - Memoirs (Institute of Social Studies Bulletin, Rand School), 1952 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Socialist Party, 1919-24, undated (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Syndicalism, undated (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Trotskyism, US - History, undated (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Biographical Sketches Compiled from American Labor Who's Who, undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Darcy, Sam: Interview Notes, undated (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Dodd, Bella: School of Darkness[ts of published book], 1954 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Labor Herald: Notes on 1920s Articles, undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Mine Workers, other), undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Notes from the Stenotype of a CP Conference Mar 31-Apr 4, 1930, undated (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Notes on the Minutes of the National Committee, TUEL, 1923-1928 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Notes on the Minutes of the Trade Union Committee of the Central Executive Committee, 1925-1927 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Notes on the Minutes of the Political Committee of the C.P., 1926-1927 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Workers Monthly: List of Articles, 1924-1927 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Bell, Daniel: The Inner World of American Socialism, undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Bell, Daniel: Letter to Max Shachtman re [attached] article in the New International, 1955 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Bellamy, Edward, undated (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Class Consciousness / Syndicalism, undated (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - De Leon, Daniel / Socialist Labor Party, undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Gompers, Samuel, undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Introduction - General, undated (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Clippings, undated (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - The New International: Issues with articles on the history of American Communism/Socialism, 1955-1956 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Origins of the Communist Party / Split in the Socialist Party, undated (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Populism, undated (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - The Proletarian Party, undated (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Socialist Party, 1900-1912, undated (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Socialist Party. Convention, Apr 1917 - Documents (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Socialist Party - War Position (WWI), undated (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Reference Queries Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Socialist Party: Daniel Bell Correspondence with, 1947 (Box 46, Folder 2)
- Series VII: Addendum
  The 1982 Addendum to the Daniel Bell Research Files on U.S. Communism, Socialism, and the Labor Movement contains material dating from 1900 to 1962, with the bulk of the items falling between 1925 and 1958. The addendum are arranged in a single continuous alphabetical series by folder heading. Folder titles are of two types: (1) subject headings retained from those used by Daniel Bell, and (2) names, derived from the author or interviewee whose material constitutes the folder's contents. A small quantity of miscellaneous publications have been filed with the collection. Most correspondence is filed together with the working documentation to which it relates, but all loose correspondence has been gathered under a folder with that heading. Correspondence of note filed within other files includes communications from Earl Browder (box 51, folder 2), Norman Thomas (box 54, folder 4), and B.J. Widdick (box 54, folder 14). Listed under Daniel Bell are drafts for his various writings. These include chapters from his study, Marxian Socialism in the United States(Princeton, 1967). Also present are extensive manuscript notes by Bell, retained together with printed material relating to them. These materials document Bell's creative process, showing how his writing evolved. Another significant strength of the addendum is the collection of interviews with prominent labor and left political figures. The Congress of Industrial Organizations is the subject of several of the interviews, and of early documentation concerning both it and constituent unions. In addition a series of "discs" have been separated from the collection. (Most of the discs contain notes sent by Bell from Paris in 1957 to the New York based study of the American Left done by The Fund for the Republic, Inc., and transcripts are present.)
  - Subseries VII:A: Writings; Research Correspondence & Materials.
    - Food Workers Industrial Union- Untitled 147 pp. typescript from Faith Denitch, undated (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - American Jewish Committee: "Communism in Crisis", undated (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Bibliographies (Books), undated (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - California C.P. Convention, May 1938 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Cogley Report (HUAC Investigation of), 1956 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Communist Party Finances - The Reporter, Jan 1951 (Box 48, Folder 5)